## harrisonndegwa65@gmail.com 0799204524 Nairobi, Kenya

# **Harrison Ndegwa**

#### Title

### **Software Engineer**

## Summary

I am an experienced software engineer with a passion for developing innovative programs that expedite the efficiency and effectiveness of organizational success. Am well-versed in technology and writing code to create systems that are reliable and user-friendly. A confident communicator, strategic thinker, and innovative creator to develop software that is customized to meet a company's organizational needs, highlight their core competencies, and further their success.

#### **Experience**

## Front End Developer

Instadriver • Nairobi, Kenya 02/2021 - 09/2021

- Oversaw and managed a team of 4 software engineers to develop and ship a vital module
- Turned figma wireframes into well designed reusable react components.
- Leveraged redux and react hooks functionalities to integrate react components with REST endpoints.

# Front End Developer

Way4Biz • Nairobi, Kenya 01/2020 - 01/2021

- In charge of developing user interface using reactjs for an e-commerce app.
- Leveraged react features and libraries like redux for state management, bootstrap as CSS framework to create good and friendly interface for users.
- Deployed MVP to Heroku for testing and presentation to the management.

# Web Developer and Designer

Pixenweb • Nairobi, Kenya 02/2018 - 12/2019

- Developed and maintained client sites using python django, Javascript J Query HTML5 and CSS3
- Created raw SQL queries to optimize db querying in PostgreSQL instance.
- Designed wordpress website ensuring responsiveness and security.
- Customized existing wordpress plugins to meet specific client needs.

#### Skills

- Javascript
- HTML
- PostgreSQL
- Typescript
- Git
- Docker
- Bootstrap
- Redux
- GraphQL

- CSS
- SQL
- Node.js
- Python
- GitHub
- CI/CD
- ReactJS / NextJS
- Linux (Ubuntu)
- Apollo GraphQL

## **Education**

_						٠		
_	^	$\sim$	n	$\sim$	m		^	c

University of Nairobi • Nairobi, Kenya 10/2021

# Languages

• English

## Github

https://github.com/HarryNdegwa

## **Personal Website**

https://www.harryndegwa.codes/

## Linkedin

https://www.linkedin.com/in/harryndegwa/